Au

ABHIJITH UDAYAKUMAR

CONTACT

E abhijithukzm@gmail.com

P +44 7442227330

A 60 Spring Gardens,

Aberdeen, UK

Abhijith14

in abhijith-udayakumar

https://abhijith14.github.io/ Portfolio-v2/ Python Dev / ML Enthusiast

PROFILE

Innovative AI / Python Developer with 4+ years of experience in application design, development, testing, and deployment. Possess an unbridled passion for Artificial Intelligence with comprehensive knowledge of machine learning concepts and other related technologies. Unmatched abilities to identify, understand, and translate program requirements into sustainable, advanced technical solutions through Python and other programming languages for continuous improvement of AI technologies.

EDUCATION

MASTER DEGREE [2022 - 2023]

University of Aberdeen, UK Artificial Intelligence

BACHELOR DEGREE [2019 - 2022]

SRM IST, INDIA Computer Applications

EXPERIENCE

CEO/FOUNDER

Buddy Developer | From 2019 to 2022

Worked on 100+ real time projects with clients across the globe. Gained experience on projects in all domains of computer science including but not limited to Automation, Data Analysis, Web Automation (Scraping Systems).

Technical & Operation Support Officer

GADS LLP | From 2020 to 2022

25+ collaborations, 20+ projects, hosted 30+ events and got 6 awards.

Head of Design and Media-Reach

LiveWires_ Students Club SRMIST | From 2019 to 2022

First ever IT club for the department of Science and Humanities, SRMIST

PROJECTS



PROJECT CVM

A COMPUTER VISION PROJECT USING GOOGLE AI



SMARTGITAUTO

A GITHUB AUTOMATION FOR MY PORTFOLIO AND REPOS



SNAKE GAME - ML

AI PAYING SNAKE GAME USING REINFORCEMENT LEARNING

ACHIEVEMENTS

Coordinated a group of students into a team by training them on various domains, who then created 100+ Websites, 100+ Applications and much more.

IBM Machine Learning Specialization 2022

Developed 95% of my skills through self education.

Won a 30 hour IEEE national level hackathon for innovative projects.

Al Appreciate/Aware 2021 - Intel India

Awarded with title of **Debugging Expert** by SRM IST

SKILLS

Python ● R ● C/C++ ● C# ● Java ● VB.NET ● SQL ● PHP ● DJANGO ● FLASK ● JS

◆ Artificial Intelligence
◆ Machine Learning
◆ Computer Vision
◆ Automation
◆ NLP
◆ Reinforcement Learning